<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2016-10-17T07:11:09-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/</id><title>Alicja Raszkowska</title><entry><title>RC - day 63</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/17/RC-day-63.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 63" /><published>2016-10-17T06:42:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-17T06:42:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/17/RC-day-63</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/17/RC-day-63.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my pull request for Zulip was merged&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;finished writing initial Outreachy proposal for Zulip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;refactored my workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pull request for Zulip stream filtering in subscriptions page was merged today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the last weekend before Outreachy application deadline and I’ve managed to finish my &lt;a href=&quot;https://paper.dropbox.com/doc/Outreachy-proposal-QfwrTnnGBDBd9hBGCyUjT#:h2=Outreachy-proposal&quot;&gt;initial proposal&lt;/a&gt; and submit the application on time. I think it will change a lot over the next three weeks, since I seem to have a lot of ideas and awareness of various needs, but need to construct smarter and more tangible goals for introducing new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With some alone time on my hands, I’ve tweaked and refactored my workflow, after reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rodrigo’s post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://rz.github.io/articles/2016/oct/time-on-your-side.html&quot;&gt;having time on your side&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an old FreeCodeCamp article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/finding-time-to-become-a-better-developer-eebc154881b2#.qvb564jid&quot;&gt;finding time to become a better developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore I’ve found a lot of inspiration while reading Dan’s list of &lt;a href=&quot;http://danluu.com/programming-books/&quot;&gt;programming books you might consider reading&lt;/a&gt;, or, as I would call it, &lt;em&gt;a list of programming books you might be so inclined as to potentially try to find a little bit, but not too much, time for, if and, only if, you are so inclined to do&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 62</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/17/RC-day-62.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 62" /><published>2016-10-17T06:37:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-17T06:37:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/17/RC-day-62</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/17/RC-day-62.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improved testing for the Zulip feature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;implemented suggested changes from the pull request&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learned better git flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I was mostly focusing on improving my Zulip pull request for stream filtering, as to make sure it gets merged into the project on time. At some point my tests started failing with Travis CI and it took some time to realize the application was not acting identically as with manual testing - the expected state was not consistent between similar tests. Atomized tests with individual set-up solved the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also learned a lot about interactive rebasing and amending commits, as to properly manage my pull request. As usual, it couldn’t have been done without Cihan’s help and support.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 61</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/16/RC-day-61.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 61" /><published>2016-10-16T06:25:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-16T06:25:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/16/RC-day-61</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/16/RC-day-61.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;algorithmic interview prep&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;one-on-one with James&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improv games&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;solving an infinite matrix problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After another all-nighter I should just start calling them ‘nights’, since I can’t seem to be able to fall asleep. Got to the apartment in the morning, slept a few hours, got back to RC and went to interview prep, which was loads of fun. I’ve asked Dan a fun brain-teaser questions I love to ask people and got one from Chris that was very satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A one-on-one with James was very helpful, since with the open format of RC it’s sometimes challenging to keep your priorities and goals in mind. After a fruitful chat, I got a ton of positive energy from improv games with Sarah and a group of wonderful Recursers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another night full of learning, talking and coding followed, with the brain-teaser on an infinite matrix taking a lot of Andy’s and my time. If you want to try it, here is the problem statement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Imagine an infinite 2-dimensional matrix containing the
    numbers 1, 2, 3, ... arranged in a diagonally winding order
    as below. Write an algorithm that returns the matrix element
    at row i and column j.

    1    3    4    10   11   21   22   36   37   55
    2    5    9    12   20   23   35   38   54   57
    6    8    13   19   24   34   39   53   58   76
    7    14   18   25   33   40   52   59   75   82
    15   17   26   32   41   51   60   74   83  101
    16   27   31   42   50   61   73   84  100  111
    28   30   43   49   62   72   85   99  112  130
    29   44   48   63   71   86   98  113  129  144
    45   47   64   70   87   97  114  128  145  163
    46   65   69   88   96  115  127  146  162  181
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’d like to check out solutions - here’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/aglee/65fa7f29bd6cccf4d4fdf2462a7c1f07&quot;&gt;Andy’s one-liner in Swift&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/trueskawka/cc22b1fa5311ff56da8c7bba41888843&quot;&gt;my solution in Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 60</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/16/RC-day-60.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 60" /><published>2016-10-16T06:11:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-16T06:11:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/16/RC-day-60</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/16/RC-day-60.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;watched community presentations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;went for the Etsy &lt;em&gt;Code as Craft&lt;/em&gt; meet-up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much fun as all-nighters are, they make it very challenging to be productive on presentation days. After getting some sleep at the apartment, I got to RC at 3:15pm, which was in perfect sync with snacks before presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marko had a great presentation about inducing hallucinations in neural networks, mainly &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/markostam/audio-deepdream-tf&quot;&gt;deep dreaming on audio spectrograms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Andrea presented his &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AndreaOrru/LaiNES&quot;&gt;NES emulator&lt;/a&gt; and reminded me of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Kirby%27s_Dream_Land&quot;&gt;Kirby&lt;/a&gt; - one of my favourite childhood games for Game Boy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tara talked about &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/taravancil/talks/blob/master/serverless-lightning.org&quot;&gt;serverless architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After presentations we went for a meet-up at Etsy, which was about mingling, great food and more presentations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leah presented the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.leahhanson.us/post/recursecenter2016/haiku_icons.html&quot;&gt;Haiku OS Vector Icon Format&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keyur talked about the data structures transformations at Etsy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emily unveiled her personal journey to creative coding, approached with a tinkering mindset&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stefanie focused on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeascraft.com/2016/09/06/api-first-transformation-at-etsy-concurrency/&quot;&gt;API-first infrastructure at Etsy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about the night was a photo booth, which we used extensively for group photos. I hope to get some more of them posted soon, for now you may enjoy a few shots of Michelle and me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;click an image to see the gallery&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/etsy/etsy_main_1.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/etsy&quot; data-title=&quot;When I find a camera, crazy things happen&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/etsy/etsy_thumb_1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;etsy_main_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/etsy/etsy_main_2.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/etsy&quot; data-title=&quot;Bonding with Michelle&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/etsy/etsy_thumb_2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;etsy_main_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 59</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/13/RC-day-59.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 59" /><published>2016-10-13T04:34:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-13T04:34:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/13/RC-day-59</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/13/RC-day-59.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;deciding on next Zulip contributions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drafting the application for Outreachy at Zulip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drafting a presentation for non-technical talks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;signed-up for algorithm prep&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;revamped my resume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having some much needed rest, I’ve focused on planning and drafting my application for Outreachy. I’ve also created a short presentation on consolidated systems of preference relations for Tuesday’s non-technical talks, which may sound intimidating, but I hope to present it in a light and fun way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, I’ve been working on my resume and expectations for next week’s job fairs. Since Outreachy deadline for applications is the upcoming Monday, I might just restrain from any other work. Especially since so much is happening at RC in the upcoming days - a meet-up at Etsy, interview prep, jobs profile building workshop, blog club, improv night and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Contra_dance&quot;&gt;contra dance&lt;/a&gt; evening.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 58</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/12/RC-day-58.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 58" /><published>2016-10-12T19:01:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-12T19:01:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/12/RC-day-58</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/12/RC-day-58.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;submitted my pull request to Zulip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;had two different American diner experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left RC at 10am today, after all night of coding and learning. I think my internal clock is completely broken by now and so is my ability to fall asleep in an instant, I’ve never cherished enough over the years. Instead of getting some much needed rest, I’ve tried and failed to watch the presidential debate and spent most of the first half of day napping between periods of reading random stuff on the Internet (some of which may be potentially useful in the future).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two days blurred into one long nap-counterpointed misc of programming and learning, with barely any socializing. Instead of going to RC in the afternoon, I met up with Cihan in a diner in Astoria. He pushed me into finishing my PR as-is, without worrying too much about it being perfect. Better early and flawed than perfect and late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I didn’t listen to him enough and was so paranoid about all tests passing all the time, I might’ve discovered a minor bug in the test suite, that made my local version of Zulip not pass the tests randomly. It turned out to be an issue unrelated to any of my changes and I’ve spend a few hours trying to figure it out and communicate the problem to Zulip team, which was a good learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’ve submitted &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zulip/zulip/pull/1983&quot;&gt;my PR&lt;/a&gt; around 4am, after checking and re-checking the code and accompanying messages for about three hours. I hope the more confident I get with open source, the less time I’ll spend on being terrified of wasting others’ time and more focused on the code quality, but I think the next few contributions are going to still be stressful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past 24 hours I’ve tried two different American diners - one very stylish (priced accordingly) and one very American-movieish. Both were fun and I felt a bit like a movie-star (or at least a supporting character/innocent bystander in Pulp Fiction). Also, milkshakes. A girl needs to have more of those on bad days (which will be evened out in my diet by less and less bad days over time due to more milkshakes).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 57</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/12/RC-day-57.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 57" /><published>2016-10-12T17:31:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-12T17:31:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/12/RC-day-57</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/12/RC-day-57.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;snapped out of an impostor syndrome episode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learned a lot about the codebase of Zulip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learned even more about the development process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very hard to start working on my Outreachy application on Tuesday. The process of learning how Zulip works, where my PR fits in the codebase and how am I to contribute something meaningful to a big project a lot of people use, was time-consuming and a bit intimidating. At some point I felt I’m not going to achieve much and should just stop pretending, giving a way in for other, more focused, talented and generally smarter people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve realised I have a severe case of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Impostor_syndrome&quot;&gt;impostor syndrome&lt;/a&gt; and it was surprising for me. I got into RC - the programming Neverland, where everything is possible and failing is learning. Where people are self-motivated and curate a growth environment, that’s welcoming and non-intimidating. Even so, I’ve managed to convince myself subconsciously I don’t belong here. That I’ve wasted so much time over the years (especially other people’s time) and all my potential and learning is going to waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s much easier to talk and share things I feel confident about. My programming is going in the right direction, but it will take years for me to feel as confident as I am with my writing or business skills. And it might never even come to that, since the environment is constantly changing and the amount of learning required to stay on the top of my ability might be incomparable to most other settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes a village to grow. I am lucky enough to have friends that care about me and know when I need a nudge in the right direction. Cihan was there again to intimidate me into working and we’ve work together all night. I didn’t finish the pull request, but I’ve learned a lot on the way and started feeling confident again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I think am at risk of being too much of a perfectionist, as ridiculous as it may sounds. I’m afraid of wasting someone’s time on a feature that’s not completely finished, so I’ll work on it more and try to push myself to share it by the end of the day on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 56</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/10/RC-day-56.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 56" /><published>2016-10-10T01:47:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-10T01:47:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/10/RC-day-56</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/10/RC-day-56.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improv class&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pairing with Cihan on merge sort&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learning how to properly use a profiler&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;half-watching the debate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NYC subway is sometimes an exercise in patience - what should take 45 minutes ends up sucking up 1.5h and there is no way to avoid it. Thankfully, as I don’t have that much time to read books at RC, I usually have a pretty good time catching up on my reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went for a free improv class at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.magnettheater.com/&quot;&gt;Magnet Theater&lt;/a&gt; and it was an amazing experience. The “yes and” attitude is something everyone needs in their life. It’s all about being aware of other people and building on what they’ve created, while constantly having fun and laughs. I’ve read a lot about it today and am thinking about getting some more improv once I’m back home. I might write something more on the topic, but since it’s so hard to put in words at the moment (also - Outreachy deadline is approaching), here is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.humorthatworks.com/learning/10-life-tips-from-improv-class/&quot;&gt;appetizer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried to watch the whole debate, but it was so repetitive and similar to everything I’ve already seen on the media, working on algorithms seemed like a better use of my time. Cihan was kind enough to pair with me on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Merge_sort&quot;&gt;merge sort&lt;/a&gt; problem for my algorithms course and I went through explaining the approach, implementing a quick solution with a horrible runtime of 35 seconds and improving it by using profiling to &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/trueskawka/a4eab263a12cbec381ef8412b56b2d9a&quot;&gt;less than 2 seconds&lt;/a&gt;. I still want to skim through the debate, just to know what people are talking about, but it’s thankfully not among my priorities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 55</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/09/RC-day-55.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 55" /><published>2016-10-09T23:57:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T23:57:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/09/RC-day-55</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/09/RC-day-55.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;entrepreneurship workshop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;playing with algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dinner at a Polish Karczma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul’s entrepreneurship workshop took up most of the day - it ran from 10:30am to about 5:30pm, though I did move on to practice algorithms around 4:30pm, as I felt I’ve done nothing most of the day. Some small exercises and brain teasers helped me stay on the programming track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening Cihan, Joe and me went for dinner at a Polish restaurant in Greenpoint. It was nice to finally be the guide and I was pleasantly surprised by how much they both liked the food, especially the lard. After the long night of stuffing ourselves to the point of being barely able to move, I went to the apartment and slept for 10 hours straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;click an image to see the gallery&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_main_1.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/polish&quot; data-title=&quot;A picture of Joe taking a picture of food&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_thumb_1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;polish_main_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_main_2.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/polish&quot; data-title=&quot;Lard and pickles&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_thumb_2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;polish_main_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_main_3.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/polish&quot; data-title=&quot;Happy Cihan&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_thumb_3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;polish_main_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_main_4.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/polish&quot; data-title=&quot;This was supposed to be for 3 people&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_thumb_4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;polish_main_4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_main_5.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/polish&quot; data-title=&quot;Boxes of food signed by Cihan&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_thumb_5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;polish_main_5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_main_6.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/polish&quot; data-title=&quot;Carroll St station&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/polish/polish_thumb_6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;polish_main_6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 54</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/07/RC-day-54.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 54" /><published>2016-10-07T23:21:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-07T23:21:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/07/RC-day-54</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/07/RC-day-54.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;interview prep&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;worked on the pull request for Zulip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;worked on my writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News of the day: &lt;strong&gt;Eva’s and Shawn’s daughter was born!&lt;/strong&gt; I’ll be visiting them next week, to flood them with love and take a million photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, nothing much else happened. I’ve lead a session on conversational interview prep and also had an algorithmic one. It always amazes me, how differently people approach the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked on the pull request for Zulip, by playing with tests and checking what breaks. My writing is not yet ready to share, but some of the long-overdue posts may appear soon (don’t want to put a date on that, since Outreachy currently has priority).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve also tried the amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http://ny.eater.com/2016/9/26/13060344/taiyaki-nyc-fish-cone-soft-serve&quot;&gt;soft-serve ice cream in fish-shaped cones&lt;/a&gt; (a Japanese treat called &lt;em&gt;taiyaki&lt;/em&gt;). The fish is a waffle filled with egg custard, which I could enjoy even without the ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week I’ve found a new apartment near Canal St (about 20-minute walk from RC). This resulted in a happy dance on the newly created Victory Dance Platform (thanks to Deniz) - a square of the shared space to do a happy dance publicly. It’s a nice way to share your joy, but I’ll probably never do it again - there were a lot of people in the space and they started clapping the moment I’ve started dancing. Most terrifying experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;click an image to see the gallery&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/other/d54/d54_main_1.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;other/d54&quot; data-title=&quot;Trying to describe the ice cream&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/other/d54/d54_thumb_1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;d54_main_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/other/d54/d54_main_2.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;other/d54&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/other/d54/d54_thumb_2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;d54_main_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/other/d54/d54_main_3.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;other/d54&quot; data-title=&quot;The Victory Dance Platform&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/other/d54/d54_thumb_3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;d54_main_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry></feed>
