<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2016-11-18T03:13:52-05:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/</id><title>Alicja Raszkowska</title><entry><title>Hot ‘Lanta</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/atlanta/2016/11/18/hot-Lanta.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hot 'Lanta" /><published>2016-11-18T02:37:31-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-18T02:37:31-05:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/atlanta/2016/11/18/hot-Lanta</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/atlanta/2016/11/18/hot-Lanta.html">My schedule will be more family-focused till November 28, when I'll be back home in Warsaw.

I got into Outreachy and will be posting the open-source posts on my official blog and Outreachy logs on a dedicated blog - I haven't set that up yet, since the internship officially starts December 6 and at the moment I'm working mostly on tasks not directly connected to my projects.

On my recent adventures in Atlanta:

- I went to visit my cousins' school for Thanksgiving lunch twice and really enjoyed it. The school is colorful and at the moment full of turkeys in all shapes and sizes. I also loved the library and the book fair at school. It seems like a lovely place to learn.

  Every child has to say and write a lot about what they are thankful for and one of my cousins said that he's thankful for his cat due to peer pressure - there is no cat. I think being grateful for what one has is a much needed tradition everywhere.

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;{% translate global.gallery %}&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
{% for img in (1..19) %}
&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/school/school_main_{{ img }}.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;school&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/school/school_thumb_{{ img }}.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;school_main_{{ img[0] }}.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
{% endfor %}
&lt;/p&gt;

- On Tuesday we went to mini Legoland - we saw how Lego blocks are made, had a ride of shooting bandits to save a princess, a tour through Lego Atlanta and loads of fun building and playing. We also went to a 4D Lego cinema, with wind blowing and snow falling.

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;{% translate global.gallery %}&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
{% for img in (1..11) %}
&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/legoland/legoland_main_{{ img }}.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;legoland&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/legoland/legoland_thumb_{{ img }}.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;legoland_main_{{ img[0] }}.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
{% endfor %}
&lt;/p&gt;

- Today we went to visit the [Stone Mountain](https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Stone_Mountain) and had a wonderful 2h hike. I was surprised that the boys went all the way up - especially little Alex in his cute Thanksgiving turkey outfit. There were all sorts of attractions, especially Christmas-themed - which was kind of amusing, since it was warm and sunny. It's a lovely summer this November. After the hike, we went down in a cable car.

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;{% translate global.gallery %}&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
{% for img in (1..13) %}
&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/mountain/mountain_main_{{ img }}.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;mountain&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/mountain/mountain_thumb_{{ img }}.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;mountain_main_{{ img[0] }}.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
{% endfor %}
&lt;/p&gt;

- After the trip we went for some delicious freshly baked Krispy Kreme donuts and got to see how they're made. There is an icing waterfall on the conveyor belt.

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;{% translate global.gallery %}&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
{% for img in (1..5) %}
&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/donuts/donuts_main_{{ img }}.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;donuts&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/donuts/donuts_thumb_{{ img }}.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;donuts_main_{{ img[0] }}.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
{% endfor %}
&lt;/p&gt;

- I've also had some time to read with my cousins, both in Polish and English. Here you can see me puzzling over a Polish ABC-book from mid-seventies.

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;{% translate global.gallery %}&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
{% for img in (1..4) %}
&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/elementarz/elementarz_main_{{ img }}.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;elementarz&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/elementarz/elementarz_thumb_{{ img }}.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;elementarz_main_{{ img[0] }}.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
{% endfor %}
&lt;/p&gt;

And now I'm relaxing and working in the most comfy of chairs.

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/workwork.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;workwork&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.cdn_path }}/atlanta/workwork_thumb.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;workwork.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>My schedule will be more family-focused till November 28, when I’ll be back home in Warsaw.</summary></entry><entry><title>Georgia on my mind</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/atlanta/2016/11/08/Georgia-on-my-mind.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Georgia on my mind" /><published>2016-11-08T04:42:31-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-08T04:42:31-05:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/atlanta/2016/11/08/Georgia-on-my-mind</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/atlanta/2016/11/08/Georgia-on-my-mind.html">Achievements (accumulated over the past few days):

* got safely and happily to Atlanta
* rested and spent a lot of quality time with family
* started helping my little cousins with their schoolwork
* refactored my Outreachy application
* worked a little bit on coding and writing
* taught my uncle some programming

The last few days have been a blur of great food and quality time with my family. I've never had a chance to visit my godmother, uncle and two little cousins in Atlanta, so I'm happy to stay here for the next three weeks. One of my grandmas is also here, so I get the benefit of loads of delicious Polish homemade food while still being in the US.

The schoolwork in the US is different - my cousins have a lot of worksheets and tests, with very detailed instructions. It's also very cute how a lot of things connect to American traditions - I've never seen so many pumpkin and turkey themed tasks.

I haven't done enough coding and writing, because I've been in the family haven. I've finally refactored my Outreachy application and project proposals - it took a lot longer than I expected, since I've decided to focus on quality time rather than development over the past week. With a lot of help from Tim, Steve and Neeraj, advice from Leah and a ton of inspiring posts and ideas from Sumana, Julia and other Recursers, I've added some details and tried to focus more on why I'm a great fit for Zulip rather than a general presentation of my skills.

I got accustomed to slow life in Atlanta suburbs (I mistakenly thought it was much closer to the city itself) and will be able to focus more on my growth again. I've had a lot of programming-related quality time today, as I showed Jerry (my uncle) [FreeCodeCamp](https://www.freecodecamp.com) and [GitHub](https://github.com/) - I'm glad that by being here I encouraged him to try it out and see if he enjoys it.

The Outreachy results will be known at 4pm UTC - which means I'll have only the next 6 hours to stress about it.</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements (accumulated over the past few days):</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - last day</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/05/RC-last-day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - last day" /><published>2016-11-05T04:41:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-05T04:41:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/05/RC-last-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/05/RC-last-day.html">Achievements:

* helped with cleaning at RC
* visited Eva, Shawn and the baby
* bought some gifts and knick-knocks
* had a midnight checkout group dinner

The never graduation party ended late, so I started my day with a long walk through Manhattan and gift shopping. The weather was perfect for simply sipping my chai latte and talking, taking a ton of photos on the way (some of them are from previous escapades).

I finally arrived to RC just in time for the cleaning party - Deniz and Isla had a wonderful idea of cleaning the shared space together. I didn't help as much as I've wanted, since I had to visit Eva and Shawn and hug the baby as the responsible auntie I am.

We went for dinner with most of our midnight checkout group and had great time, especially with very intriguing rolled ice cream at a place called Juicy Spot - they literally froze them from milk and other ingredients right before our eyes, in a magical process that included a lot of scraping.

I didn't get to say all of my goodbyes the way I've imagined them, but that may be for the best - there were so many feelings and tears in the last few days, I might've not been able to go through more.

My time in New York and physical presence at RC is over, but I'm never graduating. I need some time to write a proper return statement, as I've written so much in the past 12 weeks I'll need at least another two to go through all of it.

{% include gallery.html %}</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - never graduation</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/05/RC-never-graduation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - never graduation" /><published>2016-11-05T03:52:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-05T03:52:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/05/RC-never-graduation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/05/RC-never-graduation.html">Achievements:

* seen community presentations
* had a presentation on open-source contributions
* never graduated
* played loads of arcade games

The last day of my batch started great, with a healthy breakfast with Andy. We got some quality time, chatting away on very serious topic - much too serious for the amount of sleep we've had between ourselves.

I got back to RC just in time for presentations:

* Leah talked about [neural networks that write](https://github.com/astrieanna/LSTM_for_text), specifically [long short-term memory](https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Long_short-term_memory) networks
* Andy reminded about his Schwarzenegger's calfs project - [a documentation viewer](https://github.com/aglee/DocSetExplorer) for Apple docsets
* V presented his [content tracker in Haskell](https://github.com/vaibhavsagar/duffer), with focus on some of the different uses for his project
* Isabel talked about DNA sequences, specifically [cooperative binding](https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Cooperative_binding) and [position specific weight matrix](https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Position_weight_matrix)
* Brian showed off his cool NBA game visualiser (I'm bummed it's not available online yet)
* Trey presented his [first](https://treylawrence.github.io/idk/) p5.js [projects](https://treylawrence.github.io/gray/)

I talked about my Outreachy application process, first open-source contribution and how to start contributing to Zulip. I've also had a chance to thank everyone who's helped me with this long and challenging process and mention the Cihan alternative to the rubber duck method - he just sits there and looks disappointed whenever I'm not working.

After presentations we were handed our diplomas (Fall 2016 T-shirts) and certificates (an envelope full of niceties from Recursers). There were laughs and some tears, loads of joy and a sense of community. When I saw the Summer 2's graduation six weeks ago, I never imagined it would be such a prominent experience.

We then went for delicious burgers and spent a few hours in Barcade, playing arcade games, drinking, laughing and saying our goodbyes. It was a the best of nights.</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 80</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/05/RC-day-80.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 80" /><published>2016-11-05T03:37:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-05T03:37:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/05/RC-day-80</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/05/RC-day-80.html">Achievements:

* feelings check-in
* wrote niceties for fellow batchers
* watched **Before the Flood**
* wrote a bit

After another all-nighter I got to RC just in time for the last feelings check-in. I expected it to be very emotional, but it turned out to be much more calm and soothing. I don't feel guilty anymore that I'm ready for the next step - gradually I've started feeling more and more like a programmer. I've done very different projects from what I've planned, but still managed to fulfill my goals. A bit sad, grateful and content, I was glad others are also in a good place.

Full of feelings after the check-in, I wrote niceties for my fellow batchers. I've decided to start with those I don't know as much and slowly go through the list to my closest friends - with each person it was getting harder and harder to write. It's a happy-sad experience, since all these people mean a lot to me, but at the same time I'm sure I'll never see them again after leaving New York.

The best way to approach overflow of feelings was the dollar pizza, with a soda and brownie on top. After this joyous meal, I was unable to do anything apart from writing a little bit of my Twine story and watching [Before the Flood](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=90CkXVF-Q8M) - National Geographic film on climate change.</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 79</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/02/RC-day-79.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 79" /><published>2016-11-02T05:48:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-02T05:48:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/02/RC-day-79</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/02/RC-day-79.html">Achievements:

* had a chat with Rachel and Lyn about NaNoWriMo (inspiration!)
* got a ton of great comic recommendations
* had a lot of quality time with my fellow batchers
* organized my NaNoWriMo experience
* started my big interactive fiction story
* worked a bit on Zulip React Native app feature
* drafted a presentation on first open-source contributions

RC is full of wonders.

First, Harold gave me a book we've talked about some time ago - [Invisible Cities](http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9809.Invisible_Cities) by Italo Calvino. It was the most unexpected and delightful gift in a long time and I intend to start reading it over my morning chai latte.

Then we've had a great talk about NaNoWriMo, writing in general, comic books, regular books, elephants, history, science fiction and everything with Rachel and Lyn. If no other magical thing happened at RC so far, I'd miss it just for this one hour of pure awesomeness. Rachel took notes during our meeting (yes, it was serious business):

* some of our recent favorite books ([The Buried Giant](http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22522805-the-buried-giant) by Kazuo Ishiguro, [The Enchantress of Florence](http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1317696.The_Enchantress_Of_Florence) by Salman Rushdie, and [Hyperion](http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/77566.Hyperion) by Dan Simmons)
* setting personal goals that are independent of NaNoWriMo's goals because we're not working on traditionally structured novels
* we're going to try to write something daily
* starting an accountability stream where we check in daily as to whether we've met our goals, and weekly with excerpts of what we've written, and possibly at the end of the month with some sort of bigger reading/showcase
* COMICS, LOTS OF COMICS ([Pretty Deadly](https://imagecomics.com/comics/series/pretty-deadly), [Habibi](http://www.habibibook.com/), [Lazarus](https://imagecomics.com/comics/series/lazarus), [The Wicked + The Divine](https://imagecomics.com/comics/series/the-wicked-the-divine), [Swamp Thing](https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Swamp_Thing), [Fables](https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Fables_(comics)), [Manifest Destiny](https://imagecomics.com/comics/series/manifest-destiny) - *I am so behind on comics!*)
* some apps and tools we use for writing ([Twine](https://twinery.org/), [Scrivener](https://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener.php), [Ulysses](https://ulyssesapp.com/), Google Apps, [Scapple](https://www.literatureandlatte.com/scapple.php), notebooks, [Haven](http://www.placetowrite.com/), [Hemingway](http://beta.hemingwayapp.com/))

We've also had a fun idea of writing a blog together and I created a simple website to do just that (nothing to show yet). I was so hyped and inspired, that I noted down my goals and ideas and even went as far as to use a mind-map to do a brain-dump. I don't think I've ever written so many messages on Zulip in one evening. And the success for the day was that I actually started my interactive fiction story - at the moment I only have two characters and half of a location, but I'm doing this!

Since our never-graduation is nearing, we've also had a warm night of talking and enjoying each others company. It was more important than opening another pull request for Zulip, as the contributions I'm working on at the moment are not time-sensitive and I'll see my fellow Recursers only for the next two, three, maybe four days if I'm lucky.

Being in the mood for writing, I also drafted a presentation for Thursday on how to start contributing to open-source projects, specifically Zulip. I think it would be great to get some other RC-folks ideas and contributions, since we're all using the app heavily and will continue using it as community members. And it's great fun to learn various ideas for improvements.</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 78</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/01/RC-day-78.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 78" /><published>2016-11-01T03:31:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T03:31:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/01/RC-day-78</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/01/RC-day-78.html">Achievements:

* took part in a great workshop on Zulip React Native app
* proofread Michelle's command line tutorial
* tweaked my bash aliases

Neeraj lead a great workshop on the Zulip React Native app. First he made sure that everyone is on the same page, explaining parts of the application and answering all of our questions. He then assigned each of us small issues to fix. There were some pull requests and there is still a lot to be done.

My feature turned out to be a bit more complicated than expected, as sidebars in the mobile app have different implementations and I'm working on making them more similar. One of the challenges is to understand code written by two different developers and rewrite one of the implementations to match the approach we've decided to try, after analyzing future needs and further developments.

Michelle is writing a command line tutorial and I've been proofreading it today. It was great fun and I hope to work on it some more. She has an amazing ability to convey ideas in a non-intimidating way - it's just like having a conversation.

The proofreading inspired me to rearrange and add some bash aliases, especially used for Zulip development. I think I've invested enough in this project to have shortcuts and save some time.</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 77</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/01/RC-day-77.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 77" /><published>2016-11-01T03:13:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T03:13:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/01/RC-day-77</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/11/01/RC-day-77.html">Achievements:

* done some algorithms coursework
* played with Twine
* fixed minor website issues and refactored my Linkedin profile
* worked on debugging an issue in Zulip

It was pouring today in New York. The best part of my evening was seeping a hot chai latte under a blanket, safely hidden from the rain. The cats agreed with me, as they purred in unison on the bed, trying to get my attention and demanding cuddles.

Another stay-in day was relaxing, especially while learning some algorithms and working on my writing. I've done some little tweaks on the website, refactored my Linkedin profile a bit and decided to work on my Outreachy application tomorrow, with less sleepy brain and a fresh approach.

There is a Zulip issue possibly connected to the CSS splitting and I've been carefully looking through changes and trying out some ideas on how to fix it. I'm pretty sure it's something connected to proper CSS loading, but I haven't found a definite answer yet.

{% include gallery.html %}</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 76</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/30/RC-day-76.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 76" /><published>2016-10-30T22:31:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-30T22:31:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/30/RC-day-76</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/30/RC-day-76.html">Achievements:

* bought some gifts for friends and family
* went for Korean BBQ
* had a nice, long chat with Luna

I've finally bought some gifts - I've been here for so long, I completely forgot it's time to fly to Atlanta soon and I haven't done the shopping yet. I usually avoid walking up Broadway and lurking into the shops, but this time it was a blessing. I've checked nearly half of my list.

Afterwards we went for a great Korean BBQ evening with Cihan, Joe and Miguel. This time I was wise enough to not drink soju, as it is a sneaky beverage. One honey ice cream dessert later I headed back to RC to do some work.

I've also had a lovely chat with Luna, one of the friends I'll miss most when leaving New York. We tend to have long conversations that run for hours and we've only noticed it was time to go home around 5.30am. That's what RC does to people.

{% include gallery.html %}</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 75</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/30/RC-day-75.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 75" /><published>2016-10-30T22:22:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-30T22:22:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/30/RC-day-75</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/10/30/RC-day-75.html">Achievements:

* watched &quot;American Pastoral&quot;

I wanted to go to the Halloween party, but then there was the job fair on Thursday. The event drained me socially and I've decided to have a nice day at the apartment, reading and relaxing. This often comes as a surprise, but I'd much rather spend some time alone with a book than go to any kind of party, even though I often act extraverted. And two big social events in one week I could only do for work, as much as I love the RC community.

At some point during the evening, I've met up with Cihan and we went to the cinema in the spur of the moment. For some now unexplainable reason, we've decided to watch &quot;American Pastoral&quot; - a long, very historically grounded and uneasy movie based on the [1997 novel](https://www.wikiwand.com/en/American_Pastoral). I think I'd have to know much more about contemporary American history to understand the nuance, as I have not even read the book. I expected more from it, by the end I was a bit disappointed and lost, but so were many of the critics.</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry></feed>
