<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2016-09-29T02:56:02-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/</id><title>Alicja Raszkowska</title><entry><title>RC - day 45</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/29/RC-day-45.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 45" /><published>2016-09-29T02:20:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-29T02:20:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/29/RC-day-45</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/29/RC-day-45.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;got comfortable with Outreachy application process and narrowed down my choices to three companies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;got a working Zulip development environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;productively procrastinated on a presentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;went for a feelings check-in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visited Eva and Shawn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;signed up for a blog club and interview prep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel I’ve finally read enough about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.gnome.org/Outreachy&quot;&gt;Outreachy&lt;/a&gt; application process to feel comfortable with applying. I’ve reached out on Zulip to Sumana (experienced Outreachy mentor) and the thread helped me tremendously, especially when Alice shared her application experiences. I’ll focus on trying out the projects I’m interested in locally (or reading up about the ones that are not strictly technical), maybe even make small contributions over the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of simply procrastinating, I’ve managed to focus on science behind making decisions and quitting, inspired by an &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/galleys/optimal-stopping-45c54da6d8d0#.txu450qhe&quot;&gt;article on optimal stopping&lt;/a&gt;. I have some slides for tomorrow, but I’m not yet sure if I’m going to present - it’s not entirely a technical topic. Though knowing when to quit a project seems like a useful skill for Recursers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feelings check-in was a blast. It’s interesting how hearing about insecurities of others helps with my own struggles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited the always warm and welcoming Eva and Shawn. The baby is going to be born soon, can’t wait! Also, I might give back to my American family and help out with some web development in exchange for dinner and cheesecake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday is going to be a busy day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;interview prep - I’ve been a bit late for prep signups, so instead of algorithms I’m just going to do regular interview questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;watercolours - I’ll spend some time with Nayley on the pure pleasure of playing with paints&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blog club - we’re starting a new group at RC, encouraging each other to write more and/or better blog posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 44</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/28/RC-day-44.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 44" /><published>2016-09-28T00:00:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-28T00:00:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/28/RC-day-44</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/28/RC-day-44.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stopped forcing myself to be a morning person&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;warm-up in Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;took a few steps to build my Markdown app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improved my Gmail experience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;paired on code dojo problem with Cihan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;took part in the improv night, a fun and amazing experience (all thanks to Sarah!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;had a wonderful evening with RC friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it was high time to stop kidding myself - I am not nor will I ever be a morning person. Starting the day slowly and getting to RC just in time for my breakfast and 1pm check-in was the perfect solution to my motivation problems. Firstly, I got so much sleep I woke up without an alarm and wasn’t stressed about being late. Coming in during the day, seeing all those people working away on their laptops, focused, calm and going forward with their plans was my driving force for today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Mike, warmups are alive and well again, and I’ve had a nice half hour playing with a simple problem in Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then proceeded to plan my Markdown app - the features I want to include, people to ask for help and pair with, general look and feel of it. I’ve asked Marcio for some help on getting started and will hopefully pair soon with Nick (macOS development), Andy (macOS development and Markdown) and Michelle (Markdown filtering). Can’t wait!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for minor tweaks, I’ve spent a productive half-hour learning all the Gmail shortcuts. I have so many messages coming in every day, it’s surprising I’ve never done that before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cihan made it in time for code dojo and we’ve created together a working simple solution in Python and then struggled to reimplement it in Elm. About an hour after the dojo ended, a simplistic approach got &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/trueskawka/ba9f5dae3fd89a30b30a353b30ffee74&quot;&gt;implemented&lt;/a&gt;. I want to work more on my functional programming, since doing even the simplest things is such a struggle. It’s like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MFzDaBzBlL0&quot;&gt;relearning to ride a bike&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The improvisation night was so amazing it’s hard to describe. Sarah is such a wonderful teacher! We’ve had a lot of group and individual exercises, all of them focused on supporting each other no matter what. Improv is really about saying “yes and” to everything, I want to do more of that in programming. And a lot more improv. It could’ve also been the group - it’s not often you come up with a new theory for global warming: flying unicorns pooping ice-cream into the atmosphere (that was a very inside joke, no worries if it wasn’t clear).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the improv I went for great (and very cheap!) vegetarian food with some of my RC friends. It was firstly about bidding farewell to Naomi, but mostly it was simply an amazing evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, some food for thought:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-coffeelicious/%EF%B8%8F-write-it-anyway-f31f3ebed5e4#.f4oxuing1&quot;&gt;write it&lt;/a&gt; anyway&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themuse.com/advice/5-polite-ways-to-deal-with-people-who-notsopolitely-keep-interrupting-you&quot;&gt;politely deal with interruptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;why smart people are expected to &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/you-don-t-have-to-be-stupid-to-work-here-but-it-helps&quot;&gt;be stupid at work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;are you a &lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/40/learning/how-to-tell-if-youre-a-jerk&quot;&gt;jerk&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I seem overly amazingly and wonderfully happy recently, I should work on my adjectives starting tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 43</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/27/RC-day-43.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 43" /><published>2016-09-27T01:39:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-27T01:39:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/27/RC-day-43</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/27/RC-day-43.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;met a ton of new people today&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;watched community presentations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lost and regained a friend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;did a mob coding session&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;watched presidential debate with friends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;had a lot of quality time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was the first day of the Fall 2 2016 batch. It was amazing to meet all those new people, ready for their RC experience. It also told us a lot about our first day - we were as utterly lost and confused as we thought we were. I hope our batch can be as great guides for the newcomers, as Summer 2s were for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a friendship scare today - there was a serious risk of Cihan going back home and I actually thought it’s going to happen most of the day. I wasn’t surprised it moved me - after all, he’s one of my best friends here and it was so sudden, I expected to have six more weeks of coding and bonding. Fortunately, it turned out to be ‘only’ a scare, that got me to also bond with a lot of people. It’s surprising how close one can get to a person in such a short time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the sadness, I’ve managed to have a pretty cool mob coding session with Sarah, Leah, James and Chris. We build together a working implementation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/trueskawka/8667b12d4552c4ca46b6f79fb195c78d&quot;&gt;Hangman&lt;/a&gt; in about half an hour (mostly thanks to the mad skills of the Python experts in the group). It was fun, next time we could focus more on actual pairing and not ‘mob coding’ as such - we did a lot of thinking together and it was a bit chaotic. Looking forward to work on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was an unusual Monday, because we’ve had some presentations. As there were only five of them, I think it’s just appropriate to mention them all:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;V talked about &lt;a href=&quot;http://vaibhavsagar.com/duffer/&quot;&gt;duffer&lt;/a&gt; - his implementation of git in Haskell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marcio did a short introduction for his &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/marciok/SwiftyRuby&quot;&gt;SwiftyRuby&lt;/a&gt; - a way to use Ruby in Swift&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Andy, as hilarious as always, talked about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simplyshredded.com/oak-roots-how-arnold-turned-his-biggest-weakness%C2%97-his-calves-into-a-showcase-muscle.html&quot;&gt;Schwarzenegger’s calfs&lt;/a&gt;, in the context of his programming pop-quiz project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Michelle presented her awesome &lt;a href=&quot;http://i17on.com/&quot;&gt;intranationalization engine&lt;/a&gt; in Markdown and I want to pair with her on my app project, right after I pair with Nick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Satabdi live coded &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/satabdidas/RC_Notes/blob/65121c40b26e84a77ddc1c980e2829e9e838ad95/notes/quest_of_deep_c/tiny_elf_execs.md&quot;&gt;tiny ELF executables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all the events and talks, we all needed some alone time. At 9pm we watched the presidential debate in a side room, as to not make an official event out of it - after all politics can be a bit overwhelming for the community. It was great to see reactions of my friends, especially American ones, who do understand a lot more of it than I do. I was still very moved by it and spent a lot of time discussing it afterwards (yes, I know it was supposed to be about more pairing, but today was a social day).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, quality time dominated most of the day and I’m very happy - about new and old friends, discussions, bonding and Nutella. Yes, indulgences were on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 42</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/27/RC-day-42.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 42" /><published>2016-09-27T01:30:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-27T01:30:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/27/RC-day-42</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/27/RC-day-42.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;got new headphones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;found an apartment for the next two weeks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;had an awesome evening with RC women&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;found out what my RC pseudonym is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loved ones took most of the day today, as I spent a lot of time on Skype. It has become sort of a routine to call them at least once a week and whenever I have Internet access, I can’t miss them too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got bargain noise-cancelling over-ear headphones, which makes me very happy - bye, bye headphone headaches. I’m now completely surrounded by music and silence to work. I’ve also found a new place to stay after my current sublet. Both thanks to RC community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening, I’ve spent some time with other RC women from our and the upcoming batches. All women meetings should be more of a thing, especially in the tech community. I do miss all the women in my life a lot and it helps to have new friendships here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we apply to RC, we get automatically generated pseudonyms to reduce bias (more on this in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recurse.com/blog/43-building-a-better-and-more-diverse-community&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post by Nick). Mine is totally awesome - Feature Fog. I can’t wait to use it in a programming context soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 41</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/24/RC-day-41.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 41" /><published>2016-09-24T23:41:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-24T23:41:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/24/RC-day-41</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/24/RC-day-41.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;got a lot of rest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reflected on my first six weeks at RC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;discovered my patronus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six weeks ago I came to NYC with a very vague idea of what I wanted to do specifically. There seemed to be so many things I wanted and ‘had’ to learn - algorithms, networking, CS, ‘proper’ programming (whatever that means), machine learning, better visualisations, APIs, audio processing etc. The list could go on and on, as for the first few days I was utterly distracted and lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the first half of my batch, I’ve tried and resigned from many things. I didn’t work enough on my ‘big’ project, I felt that some methods of learning or topics I wanted to learn do not resonate with me. I’ve been going to workshops, sometimes a few a day, trying to learn as much as possible. At the same time, I was constantly amazed by the degree of focus of some of my fellow batchers, especially those who came here for ‘only’ six weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The health scare last week was a wake-up call - I’ve been overworking myself, overdosing on the wonderful experience that is RC. Yes, it was great to get up every morning full of plans and with my to-do list bursting. To rush for my morning meditation and check-in, feeling like I’m moving forward. But I need to shift my focus and adjust my goals, otherwise I might lose my motivation altogether. After all, it’s all about never graduating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, I have a few areas and goals to focus on, distilled from the vast universe of possibilities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I still want to build my language-learning app, a project I’ve spread into tiny tasks that are now somewhere near the end of my to-do list under an avalanche of ideas&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I love talking to people and I’ve been doing a lot of that, but I want to talk more about programming, which means more pairing - at least part of it should be focused on pursuing my projects&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;shortlist of bigger projects:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;language-learning app (possible pairing on audio processing, APIs and web dev)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;learning React while building an app (I have some ideas I would like to work on, especially with Ivo)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;building my own Markdown editor, either web or for MacOS&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;career goals:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;writing 10 professional blog posts by the end of my stay in the US&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;applying for the remote opportunity I’m excited about (but don’t want to write about it too much, as not to jinx it)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;having at least 2 interview prep sessions a week&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;productive procrastination:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;an ongoing list of shorter projects to learn specific programming skills&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;making small 3D printed prototypes for future DYIing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;5 hours a week for a non-programming learning project&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;spending Sundays and most of Saturdays on sightseeing/socializing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the first half of my batch was a perspective-changing experience. I’ll work on the next six weeks to be even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than reflections, plans and rest, I’ve had a fun few minutes with discovering &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pottermore.com/news/discover-your-patronus-on-pottermore&quot;&gt;my patronus on Pottermore&lt;/a&gt;. Apparently it’s a weasel, which doesn’t seem too far removed from a squirrel I’ve always imagined it to be.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 40</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/24/RC-day-40.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 40" /><published>2016-09-24T22:52:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-24T22:52:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/24/RC-day-40</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/24/RC-day-40.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;planned a mob coding session with James&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;had a great algorithms prep with Taylor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;took part in Mike’s Internet protocols workshop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tweaked my setup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;played board games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started the day perfectly with Sean’s scones, I’ve had a productive short session with James on the mob coding for the new batch on Monday. We’ll try to code a working Hangman implementation in Python in 45 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first algorithms prep was great, I don’t think I could’ve had a better partner for that than Taylor. I worked on a fairly simple matrix problem first, with some helpful feedback from Taylor, and then he got to work on a simple-turned-complicated brain teaser. I will definitely try to have more prep over the next 6 weeks and with more challenging questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike’s Internet protocols workshop (alternatively known as sniffing the glue that holds the Internet together) was comprehensive and helpful. I look forward to the next 5 or so sessions ahead of us. Mike is a great teacher! He managed to make a not so interesting topic fascinating, with a lot of examples of real-world usage and further steps for learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that I tweaked my setup a little bit, since some fellow Recursers had problems with reading my syntax highlighting during pairing. Too be fair, the tiny-tiny letters on my screen are not of much help either, but since there is a simple enough shortcut for that, I’m not going to change it just yet. My bash prompt welcomes me now with a little heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/other/bash_prompt.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed quite late at the RC, playing board games and solving problems in our apps (but mostly board games). I love the space so much, I sometimes wish I could just not sleep at all.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 39</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/24/RC-day-39.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 39" /><published>2016-09-24T22:14:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-24T22:14:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/24/RC-day-39</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/24/RC-day-39.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;worked with Jeni, Alicia and Satabdi on the sexism tracking app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abstract Salad Factory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MCed presentations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;had fun at the farewell picnic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;walked through the Brooklyn Bridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The productive part of the day was really short, since today we had a farewell picnic for the Summer 2 batch (who overlapped with us) and some of our fellow batchers from Fall 1, who came here only for six weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve managed to get some coding started on our sexism tracking app, pairing with Jeni on views. The Abstract Salad Factory helped me then with not feeling guilty about indulging myself during the presentations and the picnic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I volunteered to MC the presentations, i.e. being the master of ceremonies - introducing speakers and making sure everything works out. It was fun, albeit a bit stressful. I had to come up to every person that was presenting, interrupt their last touchups and make sure their laptops work with the projector, the loudspeakers won’t make everybody’s ears bleed and they have whatever they might need. Even though I’ve had a few missteps on the way, everything ran pretty smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presentations themselves were hilarious, some of my favourites were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lareine’s implementation of ethical engineering algorithm, with some surprising turns on who “deserves” to live - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/8yd8d0ynkw25oxx/Ethical%20Engineering.pptx&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; are some of her thoughts from the previous presentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jesse’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/JesseRap/RoboDJ&quot;&gt;DJ app&lt;/a&gt;, on which he worked together with Taylor - it automatically mixes music, just as a DJ would&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Michelle’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://i17on.com/&quot;&gt;intranationalization engine for Markdown&lt;/a&gt;, which she hilariously presented with examples of possible uses of filtering words in text (e.g. you might want your resume to be “tech” for some people, but “fun” for others)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Juan’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jhbabon/johnny_eight&quot;&gt;CHIP-8&lt;/a&gt; emulator, which he got to play pong!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to the Brooklyn Bridge park and had a few wonderful hours in the sun, eating snacks and playing some outdoor sports. I learned to throw the egghand (Americans would call it football), but I need to work on not getting hit in the face with it. Also, a squirrel was very into our cookies and she was very impatient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also tried an American burger for the very first time and the experience was a bit disturbing - it tasted like something twice deep-fried. Striving to have more NYC experiences, I went on a walk through Brooklyn Bridge, or rather was dragged through it with the help of Cihan and Joe. It is ver high and the sidewalk is made of wood, my fear of heights won’t let me forget about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;click an image to see the gallery&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_main_1.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/picnic&quot; data-title=&quot;Brooklyn bridge&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_thumb_1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;picnic_main_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_main_2.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/picnic&quot; data-title=&quot;A wonderful place to have a picnic&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_thumb_2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;picnic_main_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_main_3.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/picnic&quot; data-title=&quot;A squirrel joined us for cookies&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_thumb_3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;picnic_main_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_main_4.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/picnic&quot; data-title=&quot;She was not scared at all&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_thumb_4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;picnic_main_4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_main_5.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/picnic&quot; data-title=&quot;And very fluffy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_thumb_5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;picnic_main_5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_main_6.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/picnic&quot; data-title=&quot;Manhattan&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_thumb_6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;picnic_main_6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_main_7.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/picnic&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_thumb_7.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;picnic_main_7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumb-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_main_8.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;bonding/picnic&quot; data-title=&quot;The American (or, as I would call it, 'deep-fry it twice') burger&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/56085440/photos/bonding/picnic/picnic_thumb_8.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumb-img&quot; alt=&quot;picnic_main_8.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 38</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/22/RC-day-38.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 38" /><published>2016-09-22T02:35:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-22T02:35:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/22/RC-day-38</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/22/RC-day-38.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;worked with Alicia, Jeni and Satabdi on the sexism-tracking app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brian’s workshop on RESTful API design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nick’s workshop on macOS development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;refactored my code with Cihan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;written niceties for fellow Recursers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a pretty good feeling about our sexism-tracking app. It seems self-contained, pretty well planned and it will hopefully turn out to be useful - I’m especially up for doing a lot of data visualisation. The first session was mostly about setting up the environment and I went down the rabbit hole with the virtual environment, as it didn’t like to have a space in the path name for my app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian’s workshop on RESTful API design was concise and well planned, I’ll be using his notes shortly. Nick has provided us with such a vast amount of knowledge on macOS development, I’ll need to pair with him soon to wrap my mind around it. I’ve always wanted to have my own Markdown writing app, so it fits perfectly with my programming bucket list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I didn’t feel productive enough, I’ve had an impromptu session of refactoring my JS calendar with Cihan. He’s a great pairing navigator - intimidating me into working on my code by sitting and waiting for me to answer my own questions (this was not sarcastic, he’s so much fun to work with!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also spent an hour on writing niceties for our fellow Recursers, whose (half-)batch is ending soon. It was wonderful to be able to share all the feelings and gratitude, but also sad to think they’ll be gone soon. Alas, you can never be truly gone from the RC community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over all, the day went pretty great, even though I didn’t make it for today’s experimental check-in. I didn’t plan for it, it’s just that yesterday evening I met Luna - an RC alumni - with whom I’ve spend a better part of three hours completely lost in conversation and didn’t get back to the apartment soon enough to wake up on time. I think it falls into the category of “first world problems” - I have so many amazing people to meet and talk to that I can’t find time to sleep or be productive enough. I’ve done it yet again during the day - an innocent conversation with John turned into a 1.5h+ experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 37</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/22/RC-day-37.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 37" /><published>2016-09-22T02:20:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-22T02:20:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/22/RC-day-37</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/22/RC-day-37.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learned more about Django REST framework&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;V’s workshop on Git Internals in Git&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read a hilarious article on Ruby vs Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;planned a mob coding session for the new batch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the sexism-tracking app will be built in Django, I wanted to learn more about the REST framework. The RESTful API design workshop was moved till Wednesday, so I’ll probably work on it a little bit more during the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;V had a cool workshop on Git internals done entirely in Git. I didn’t feel I knew enough to understand and appreciate it enough, but I’ll definitely go through it again as soon as I have some time to watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YUCwr1Y6bFI&quot;&gt;Emily’s presentation on Git&lt;/a&gt;, as I’ve heard it might be very helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, I was mostly browsing and organising. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/ruby-vs-python-the-definitive-faq-5cb0046292be#.adrdav245&quot;&gt;hilarious article&lt;/a&gt; on Ruby vs Python made my evening. Following into Alicia’s footsteps, I’ve decided to do a mob coding session for the new batch on Monday and I’m still looking for just the right challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry><entry><title>RC - day 36</title><link href="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/20/RC-day-36.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC - day 36" /><published>2016-09-20T00:20:31-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-20T00:20:31-04:00</updated><id>https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/20/RC-day-36</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://trueskawka.github.io/usa/rc/log/2016/09/20/RC-day-36.html">&lt;p&gt;Achievements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;started the week right with experimental check-in group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;paired with Ivan on improving blog loading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;worked on an app concept with Alicia, Isla and Juan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;took part in Lyn’s OpenGL workshop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;discussed my next portfolio + blog steps with Jeni&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;had some inspiration for growing as a programmer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experimental check-in group is about accountability, so we’ve started the week with assigning each other a person to help us and someone we could help with their work. I got a lot of support from Jeni on my writing and discussed Aissam’s app with him (though I don’t feel I’ve helped him much).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve also done the initial planning for our problem-tracking app - we’re going to set it up in Django and do the initial functionality in plain HTML + CSS, to be further improved with proper JS (we might even try a JS framework, though it seems like a lot of work for a tiny app).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, the OpenGL workshop brought some inspiration, but I’m afraid I don’t have enough time for it now, with all the career- and CS-focused tasks ahead. I have some ideas on my next career steps, but I need to clarify and commit to them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alicja</name></author><summary>Achievements:</summary></entry></feed>
